Guide to the Alyse Gregory Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Series V, Photographs, (boxes 63-66), is organized into four subseries: Albums, People, Places, and Photograph Envelopes. Two albums are present, including a volume of uncaptioned photographs, apparently made during Gregory's early travels in Europe, ca. 1905. This album includes images of Gregory and Marie Hippolyte Ponsin Rôze, as well as many unidentified people. A second album contains captioned photographs made by unidentified travelers during a cruise to Indonesia, ca. 1920, including images of shipboard scenes and views of Palestine, Port Said, Algiers, Pedang, and other locations in Indonesia.
The second subseries, People, includes several copies of a late snapshot of Gregory, and an early portrait of her and Marianne Moore in the Dial offices, taken by Doris Ulmann. Several photographs, including one image of Llewelyn Powys and several of unidentified people and places, appear to have been taken in Switzerland. Other items include several photographs of Laure Hayman, a friend of Marcel Proust, sent to Gregory by Henriette Metcalf; a photograph of John Cowper Powys with an unidentified man; a group of photographs of William Powys and his family; many photographs of correspondents represented in Series I; and a few photographs of East Chaldon neighbors. Also present are many family photographs sent to Gregory by James Sibley Watson, Jr., dating from the 1950s-60s, showing himself, his wife Hildegarde Lasell Watson, and their children and grandchildren.
The third subseries, Places, consists of a few photographs of Gregory's last home at Velthams Cottage and of unidentified houses. The last subseries, Photograph Envelopes, contains envelopes from English and Swiss film developers.
Series VI, Artworks, (box 67), arranged alphabetically by artist, consists of a small number of reproductions and original works, mostly correspondents represented in Series I. Other materials include original engravings by Robert Gibbings and Stephen Gooden.
Series VII, Clippings and Other Printed Material, (box 68), contains subject files arranged alphabetically. Most subjects are names of people represented in Series I, with materials including clippings by and about the person, and in some cases typed transcripts of published poems. Other materials include clippings relating to Gregory's marriage, a small scrapbook of clippings about her father's death, a printed map showing East Chaldon and Chydyok, a Dial clip sheet from 1925, and a few clippings about The Dial and Patchin Place.
Series VIII, Other Alyse Gregory Papers, (box 69), is arranged alphabetically by type of material. Materials relating to Gregory and Llewelyn Powys include a typescript note left by Gregory at her death; lists of Powys's manuscripts owned by her; locks of Powys's hair, legal documents concerning his autopsy and estate; and notes of conversation with Powys taken by Gregory at his deathbed. Also present are address books, notes concerning the Gregory and Pinneo families, an essay about John Redwood Anderson by Frank Merrick, and a scrapbook made by Annetta Mullins, a friend of Gregory who was mentally ill.
Series IX, Papers of Others Held by Alyse Gregory, (boxes 70-74), is organized into four subseries: Llewelyn Powys Papers, Edna St. Vincent Millay Writings, John Cowper Powys Writings, and Gertrude Powys Diaries.
The largest subseries, Llewelyn Powys Papers, is organized into subgroups of Correspondence, Diaries, Writings, and Other Papers. Most correspondence consists of transcripts prepared by Gregory from Powys's outgoing letters, for which originals are not present. Transcripts, some with notes by Gregory, include early letters to his family, letters written to literary friends, and replies to requests for his advice and philosophic views. A smaller amount of original incoming and outgoing letters includes many names also represented in Gregory's correspondence in Series I. Concentrations of transcripts and originals are present for Gerald Brenan, H. Rivers Pollock, John Cowper Powys, Littleton Powys, and Philippa Powys.
The second subgroup, Diaries, includes a diary kept during travel to Palestine in 1928-29, two later diaries with a few brief entries, and typescripts of extracts from early diaries, prepared by Gregory. Writings includes essays, mainly typed transcripts made by Gregory and Kenneth Hopkins, clippings of book reviews written by Powys for the New York Herald Tribune, and proofreading notes made by Gregory and John Cowper Powys. The final subgroup, Other Llewelyn Powys Papers, consists of a notebook of Francis Bacon quotations written by Powys's friend May Chesshire, with a presentation inscription from Powys, and clippings and transcripts of articles about Powys and his writings.
Edna St. Vincent Millay Writings includes holograph poems sent to Llewelyn Powys by Millay; poems from Buck in the Snow, transcribed by Powys in holograph; and typescript drafts of poems from Huntsman, What Quarry? and Wine From These Grapes. John Cowper Powys Writings consists of a small amount of materials, including a draft of his introduction to A Baker's Dozen, a collection of essays by Llewelyn Powys, and drafts of a memoir of Llewelyn, apparently written late in John Cowper's life. Gertrude Powys Diaries consists of several printed pocket diaries with brief entries, arranged chronologically. The diaries were kept during her later years at Chydyok with Gregory and Philippa Powys.
Series X, Rosemary Manning Papers, (box 75), is organized into two subseries: Correspondence and Other Papers. Correspondence concerns Gregory's death, memories of her, and Manning's interest in publishing Gregory's papers. Most items are incoming letters from friends of Gregory also represented in Series I. Also present are letters and notes from Gregory concerning her estate. Other items include letters from Ark Press, Donald Gallup, Richard Perceval Graves, Alan Parkes, and other publishers and Powys associates. The second subseries, Other Papers, includes reviews of The Cry of a Gull; clippings concerning Gregory, The Dial, and the Powys family; and notes made by Manning concerning Gregory's papers.
Dial (Chicago, Ill.); American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; English literature -- 20th Century; Social movements -- United States; Women authors, American -- 20th Century; Women -- Suffrage -- United States; Davos (Switzerland); Devon (England) -- Social life and customs; Dorset (England) -- Social life and customs; Indonesia -- Description and travel; Norwalk (Conn.); Engravings (prints); Photographs; Abbott, Claude Colleer, 1889-1971; Anderson, John Redwood, 1883-1964; Benét, William Rose, 1886-1950; Bourne, Randolph Silliman, 1886-1918; Brenan, Gerald, 1894-1987; Brooks, Gladys; Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963; Casey, Mary; Collins, Vere H. (Vere Henry), 1872-1966; Costigan, Giovanni, 1905-1990; De Lima, Agnes; De Lima, Sigrid, 1921-1999; Du Cann, C. G. L. (Charles Garfield Lott), 1889-; Elwin, Eve; Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1883-1945; Ficke, Gladys Brown, 1890-1973; Gregory, Alyse, 1884-1967; Gregory, James G., d. 1932; Gregory, Jean L. Pinneo; Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947; Hardy, Evelyn, 1902-; Hayman, Laure, Mme., 1851-; Hopkins, Kenneth, 1914-; Leon, Derrick, 1908-1944; Manning, Rosemary; Marlow, Louis, 1881-1966; Maxwell, William Q.; Metcalf, Henriette; Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; Nordlinger, Marie, 1876-1961; Penny, Lucy Powys; Playter, Phyllis; Potocki de Montalk, Geoffrey, Count; Powys, A. R. (Albert Reginald), 1881-1936; Powys, Gertrude M. (Gertrude Mary); Powys, John Cowper, 1872-1963; Powys, Littleton, 1874-1955; Powys, Llewelyn, 1884-1939; Powys, Marian, 1882-1972; Powys, Philippa, 1886-1963; Powys, Theodore Francis, 1875-1953; Powys, William; Proust, Marcel, 1871-1922; Rôze, Marie Hippolyte Ponsin; Scott-Maxwell, Florida, 1883-1979; Sergeant, Elizabeth Shepley, 1881-1965; Thayer, Scofield, 1889-1982; Warner, Sylvia Townsend, 1893-1978; Watson, Hildegarde Lasell, -1976; Watson, James S. (James Sibley), 1894-1982; Wilkinson, Joan Lambert; Wilkinson, Louis, 1881-1966; Wilkinson, Oliver Marlow; Woolsey, Gamel; Gregory family; Pinneo family; Powys family
- Correspondence, 1898-1967; Series I; 23.05; (54 boxes)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - "A"-"G" general, 1952-67, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "H"-"Z" general, 1916-67, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Abbott, Claude Colleer, 1939 Dec-47 Oct (Box 1, Folder 3-16)
    - Abbott, Claude Colleer, 1947 Nov-51 Oct (Box 2, Folder 17-32)
    - Abbott, Claude Colleer, 1951 Nov-56 Dec (Box 3, Folder 33-48)
    - Abbott, Claude Colleer, 1957 Jan-61 Mar (Box 4, Folder 49-64)
    - Abbott, Claude Colleer, 1961 Apr-64 Jul (Box 5, Folder 65-80)
    - Abbott, Claude Colleer, 1964-67, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 81-96)
    - Ackland, Valentine, 1939-67, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 97-113)
    - Ackland, Valentine (Box 8, Folder 114-120)
    - Adams, Thomas R.
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: University of Pennsylvania. Theodore Dreiser Committee, Box 38, folder 672
    - Anderson, Gwyneth Barrett, 1964-67, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 121-122)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes transcripts of letters from John Redwood Anderson to AG
      See also: Anderson, John Redwood, Box 9, folders 132-135
    - Anderson, John Redwood, 1943 Feb-48 Jun (Box 8, Folder 123-131)
    - Anderson, John Redwood, 1948-63, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 132-135)
      Some letters from JRA written partly by Gwyneth Barrett Anderson
      See also: Anderson, Gwyneth Barrett, Box 8, folders 121-122
    - Anderson, John Redwood (transcripts), 1943-54, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 136-137)
    - Bax, Clifford, 1949 Jul 14 (Box 9, Folder 138)
    - Beaver, Harold, 1962 Dec 2 (Box 9, Folder 139)
    - Benét, William Rose, 19[40?]-49, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 140)
    - Bennett, Elizabeth, 1964 Jul 5 (Box 9, Folder 141)
    - Berry, Elizabeth, 1944, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 142)
    - Bissell, E. E., 1957-66 (Box 9, Folder 143)
    - Blodgett, Dorothy, 1965-67, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 144-147)
    - Boissevain, Eugen, 1936-[48?], n.d. (Box 9, Folder 148-149)
    - Bourne, Randolph Silliman, 1913 Jun-14 Sep (Box 9, Folder 150-151)
    - Bourne, Randolph Silliman, 1914-18, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 152-154)
    - Bourne, Randolph Silliman (to [Esther Cornell?]), 1918 Aug 2 (Box 10, Folder 155)
    - Bourne, Randolph Silliman (transcripts), 1913-14 (Box 10, Folder 156)
    - Bradfield, Donald, 1961-66, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 157-158)
    - Brenan, Gerald, 1932-67, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 159-168)
    - Brenan, Gerald, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 169-173)
    - Brenan, Helen (to Gerald Brenan), n.y. Jul 19 (Box 11, Folder 174)
    - Brenan, Miranda (Box 11, Folder 175)
    - Brooks, Eleanor, 1939, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 176)
    - Brooks, Gladys, 1954-67, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 177-183)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1919-61, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 184)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck (transcripts), 1919-61, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 185)
    - Brophy, Brigid, 1965 Jul 22 (Box 11, Folder 186)
    - Burke, Kenneth, 1966 Nov 25 (Box 11, Folder 187)
    - Burroughs, Betty, 1926-44, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 188-189)
      Includes an undated letter written on a photograph of Thomas F. Woodhouse II (BB's son)
    - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1939 Dec 6 (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - Canby, Marian Ponsonby Gause, 1959-61 (Box 12, Folder 191)
    - Casey, Mary, 1941 Jun-45 Aug (Box 12, Folder 192-201)
    - Casey, Mary, 1945-65, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 202-203)
    - Churchill, Allen, 1961 Nov 17 (Box 12, Folder 204)
    - Collins, Vere H. (Vere Henry), 1944-62, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 205-208)
    - Connolly, Cyril
      See Horizon, Box 17, folder 300
    - Costigan, Amne
      See: Costigan, Giovanni, Boxes 12-13, folders 209-219
    - Costigan, Giovanni, 1954 Jul-58 Aug (Box 12, Folder 209-210)
      Includes letters from Amne Costigan
    - Costigan, Giovanni, 1958-67, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 211-219)
    - Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin), 1953 Feb 9 (Box 13, Folder 220)
    - Cummings, Marion Morehouse, 1960 Nov 26 (Box 13, Folder 221)
    - Curry, Madeleine Walker, 1939-57, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 222-228)
    - Degenhardt, A. H., 1948,65 (Box 14, Folder 229)
    - de Lima, Agnes, 1965-66 (Box 14, Folder 230)
    - de Lima, Sigrid, 1965, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 231)
    - Du Cann, C. G. L. (Charles Garfield Lott), 1940-64, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 232-237)
    - Ellis, A. E.
      See: Lindsay, Derek, Box 18, folders 309-315
    - Elwin, Eve, 1948-67, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 238-242)
    - Elwin, Malcolm, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 243)
    - Empson, Patience, 1962 Aug 7 (Box 14, Folder 244)
    - Faber, Geoffrey (to "my dear Collins"), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 245)
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1934-44 (Box 14, Folder 246)
    - Ficke, Gladys Brown, 1966 May 1 (Box 14, Folder 247)
    - Fisher, Jeanetta, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 248)
    - Fisher, John, 1941 Oct-61 Mar (Box 15, Folder 249-264)
    - Fisher, John, 1961-67, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 265-280)
    - [Fisher?], Juanita, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 281)
    - Gibbings, Robert, 1940-57 (Box 17, Folder 282)
    - Gibbon, Mark, 1953-65 (Box 17, Folder 283)
    - Gooden, Mona, 1943-57, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 284)
    - Gooden, Stephen, 1946-52, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 285)
    - Gowing, Lawrence, 1950-59, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 286)
    - Green, Pauline, 1962, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 287)
    - Greene, Sigrid
      See: de Lima, Sigrid, Box 14, folder 231
    - Grey, Peter Powys, 1959-67, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 288)
    - Grey, Tyler, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 289)
    - Gujer, Lisaly, 1965 Sep 11 (Box 17, Folder 290)
    - Häberlin, F., 1965 Dec 18 (Box 17, Folder 291)
    - Hardy, Evelyn, 1963-66, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 292-293)
    - Henderson, Hilary (Box 17, Folder 294)
    - Holahan, Anne, 1935-38, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 295)
    - Holloway, Margaret, 1956-66, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 296-297)
    - Holloway, Mark, 1951-67 (Box 17, Folder 298-299)
    - Hopkins, Kenneth
      See: Woolsey, Gamel (transcripts), Box 50, folder 858
    - Horizon, 1944, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 300)
      Written by Anna Kavan
    - Johnson, Alvin Saunders, 1948 Mar 15 (Box 17, Folder 301)
    - Kavan, Anna
    - Leon, Derrick, 1941-42 Sep (Box 17, Folder 302-305)
    - Leon, Derrick, 1942-44, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 306-308)
    - Lindsay, Derek, 1959-66 (Box 18, Folder 309-315)
    - London Magazine, 1958 Jan 23 (Box 18, Folder 316)
      Written by James Wright
    - Manning, Rosemary, 1958-66, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 317)
    - Marks, Isobel Powys, 1963, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 318)
    - Marlow, Louis
      See: Wilkinson, Louis, Boxes 41-42, folders 729-747
    - Marsh, Reginald, 1952 Feb 14 (Box 18, Folder 319)
    - Maxwell, William Q., 1965-67, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 320-321)
    - Metcalf, Addison M., 1965 May 24 (Box 18, Folder 322)
    - Metcalf, Henriette, 1956 Jan-58 Dec (Box 18, Folder 323-325)
    - Metcalf, Henriette, 1959-67, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 326-339)
    - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1935-46, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 340)
    - Mitchison, Naomi, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 341)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1925-36 Feb (Box 19, Folder 342-344)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1936-66, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 345-349)
    - Moore, Mary Warner, 1927 Jun 26 (Box 20, Folder 350)
    - Mortimer, Raymond, 1944-51 (Box 20, Folder 351)
    - Mullins, Annetta, 1947-56, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 352)
    - Mullins, Annetta (from others), 1947 Jun-Jul (Box 20, Folder 353)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1938-58 (Box 20, Folder 354)
    - Newman, Peggy, 1940 Jun-61 Mar (Box 20, Folder 355-360)
    - Newman, Peggy, 1961-67, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 361-367)
    - Nordlinger, Marie, 1942-59 Jan (Box 21, Folder 368-376)
    - Nordlinger, Marie, 1959-61, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 377)
    - Osbourne, Alan, 1958-65 (Box 22, Folder 378-381)
    - Painter, George Duncan, 1961 Jan 3 (Box 22, Folder 382)
    - Parady, Rex Dennis (to John Cowper Powys), 1957 Sep 26 (Box 22, Folder 383)
    - Penny, Lucy Powys, 1963-67, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 384-388)
    - Penny, Lucy Powys (to John Cowper Powys), 1932 Aug 10 (Box 22, Folder 389)
    - Penny, Mary
      See: Casey, Mary, Box 12, folders 192-203
    - Playter, Phyllis, 1925 Apr-48 May (Box 22, Folder 390-396)
    - Playter, Phyllis, 1949 Mar-57 May (Box 23, Folder 397-412)
    - Playter, Phyllis, 1957 Jun-59 Sep (Box 24, Folder 413-427)
    - Playter, Phyllis, 1959 Oct-63 Apr (Box 25, Folder 428-441)
    - Playter, Phyllis, 1963 May-64 Dec (Box 26, Folder 442-455)
    - Playter, Phyllis, 1965 Jan-66 Aug (Box 27, Folder 456-469)
    - Playter, Phyllis, 1966-67, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 470-483)
    - Playter, Phyllis, 1965 Aug-66 Aug (Box 29, Folder 484-488)
    - Playter, Phyllis (to Isobel Powys Marks), [1963] Apr 29 (Box 29, Folder 489)
    - Playter, Phyllis (to Penny, Lucy Powys), [1963] Apr-May (Box 29, Folder 490)
    - Potocki de Montalk, Geoffrey, Count (transcript), 1965 May 10 (Box 29, Folder 491)
    - Potocki de Montalk, Geoffrey, Count (to Lucy Powys Penny), 1964 Sep 1-21 (Box 29, Folder 492)
    - Powys, A. R. (Albert Reginald) ("Bertie") (transcripts), 1926-35, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 493)
    - Powys, Elizabeth, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 494)
    - Powys, Faith Oliver, 1936-67, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 495-497)
    - Powys, Francis, 1963-67. n.d. (Box 29, Folder 498-502)
    - Powys, Gertrude M. (Gertrude Mary), 1928-41 Jun (Box 29, Folder 503-504)
    - Powys, Gertrude M. (Gertrude Mary), 1942-45, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 505-506)
    - Powys, Gilfrid, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 507)
    - Powys, Isobel
      See: Marks, Isobel Powys, Box 18, folder 318
    - Powys, John Cooper, 1924 Sep-42 Jun (Box 30, Folder 508-522)
    - Powys, John Cooper, 1942 Jul-46 Oct (Box 31, Folder 523-537)
    - Powys, John Cooper, 1946-58, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 538-552)
    - Powys, John Cooper, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 553-556)
    - Powys, John Cowper (to Jean L. Gregory Byington, n.y. Oct 20 (Box 33, Folder 557)
    - Powys, John Cowper (to Gertrude M. Powys), 1933 May 14 (Box 33, Folder 558)
    - Powys, John Cowper (to Gertrude M. Powys, transcripts), 1923-37, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 559)
    - Powys, John Cowper (draft, to an unidentified recipient), n.d. (Box 33, Folder 560)
    - Powys, Katie
      See: Powys, Philippa, Box 34, folders 572-577
    - Powys, Littleton, 1939-44 (Box 33, Folder 561)
    - Powys, Llewelyn, 1924-39, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 562-569)
    - Powys, Llewelyn (transcripts), 1934-39, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 570)
    - Powys, Lucy
      See: Penny, Lucy Powys, Box 22, folders 384-389
    - Powys, Marian, 1940, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 571)
    - Powys, Philippa, 1928-62, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 572-577)
    - Powys, Sally, 1964-65 (Box 34, Folder 578)
    - Powys, Susan
      See: Powys, Theodora Gay, Box 34, folder 579
    - Powys, Theodora Gay, 1964 Oct 3 (Box 34, Folder 579)
    - Powys, Theodore Francis, 1940 Feb 24 (Box 34, Folder 580)
    - Powys, Violet Dodds, 1948-63, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 581)
    - Powys, William (Box 34, Folder 582-585)
    - Quennell, Peter, 1942-45, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 586)
    - Read, Herbert, 1959 May 25 (Box 34, Folder 587)
    - Riccius, Hermann P., 1927, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 588)
    - Richards, Kristine, 1960-66, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 589-590)
    - Robertson, Maurice, 1916-22, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 591)
    - [Robinson?], Aileen, 1963-65 (Box 34, Folder 592)
    - Rose, Rosamond, 1936 Jan-Aug (Box 34, Folder 593-594)
    - Rose, Rosamond, 1936-57, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 595-612)
    - Rose, Rosamond (Box 36, Folder 613-615)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1937 Jan 10 (Box 36, Folder 616)
    - Rôze, Marie Hippolyte Ponsin, 1901 Apr 10 (Box 36, Folder 617)
    - Russell, Bertrand, 1929 Apr 30 (Box 36, Folder 618)
    - Russell, Bertrand (to Gamel Woolsey), 1957-58 (Box 36, Folder 619)
    - Santayana, George, 1938-40 (Box 36, Folder 620)
    - Santayana, George (transcripts), 1938-40, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 621)
    - Scott-Maxwell, Florida, 1936-66, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 622-631)
    - Scott-Maxwell, Florida (transcripts), 1910-58 Jan (Box 36, Folder 632-636)
    - Scott-Maxwell, Florida (transcripts), 1958-65, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 637-645)
    - Sergeant, Elizabeth Shepley, 1960-65, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 646)
    - Stein, Gertrude, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 647)
    - Stern, James, 1963-67 (Box 37, Folder 648)
    - Stewart, Meum, 1955 Jan 6 (Box 37, Folder 649)
    - Stoner, Oliver, 1943-49 Jul (Box 37, Folder 650-655)
    - Stoner, Oliver, 1949-67, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 656-659)
      Includes documents concerning AG's death
    - Thayer, Scofield, 1921-26, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 660-666)
    - Thayer, Scofield (to Miss [Philippa?] Powys), 1926 Sep 6 (Box 38, Folder 667)
    - Thayer, Scofield (to Gilbert Seldes), 1922 Nov 28 (Box 38, Folder 668)
    - Thayer, Scofield (to Charles Thayer), n.d. (Box 38, Folder 669)
    - Toynbee, Philip, 1956 Apr 28 (Box 38, Folder 670)
    - Tracy, Honor (to Gamel Woolsey), 1962, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 671)
    - University of Pennsylvania. Theodore Dreiser Committee, 1950 May 24 (Box 38, Folder 672)
      Written by Thomas R. Adams
    - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1965 May 2 (Box 38, Folder 673)
    - Warburton, Angela, 1964-67 (Box 38, Folder 674-675)
    - Ward, Richard H., 1951 May 23 (Box 38, Folder 676)
    - Warner, Sylvia Townsend, 1936 Jan-51 Aug (Box 38, Folder 677-678)
    - Warner, Sylvia Townsend, 1951-67, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 679-692)
    - Wasserstrom, William, 1964 Feb 25 (Box 39, Folder 693)
    - Watson, Hildegarde Lasell, 1948-67 (Box 39, Folder 694-695)
    - Watson, James Sibley, Jr., 1921-67, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 696-705)
    - Wilkinson, Ann Reid, 1929 Jun 18 (Box 40, Folder 706)
    - Wilkinson, Joan Lamburn, 1941 Jul-49 Jul (Box 40, Folder 707-712)
    - Wilkinson, Joan Lamburn, 1949-57, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 713-725)
    - Wilkinson, Joan Lamburn (transcripts), 1942-49, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 726-728)
      With notes, 1961-65, n.d.
    - Wilkinson, Louis, 1936-45 Feb (Box 41, Folder 729-730)
    - Wilkinson, Louis, 1945-66, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 731-740)
      Includes letters written for LW by Oliver Wilkinson
    - Wilkinson, Louis (transcripts), 1937-58, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 741-747)
      With notes, 1963 and n.d.
    - Wilkinson, Oliver Marlow, 1965-67 (Box 43, Folder 748-749)
      See also: Wilkinson, Louis, Box 42, folders 731-740
    - Williams, Constance, 1948, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 750)
    - Williamson, C. P., 1967 Jul 21 (Box 43, Folder 751)
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1941-52 (Box 43, Folder 752)
    - Wittenberg, Sophia, 1950 Mar 7 (Box 43, Folder 753)
    - Woolsey, Gamel, 1930 Aug-43 Oct (Box 43, Folder 754-765)
    - Woolsey, Gamel, 1944 Feb-50 Oct (Box 44, Folder 766-780)
    - Woolsey, Gamel, 1950 Nov-54 Aug (Box 45, Folder 781-795)
    - Woolsey, Gamel, 1954 Oct-60 Aug (Box 46, Folder 796-810)
    - Woolsey, Gamel, 1960 Sep-67 Aug (Box 47, Folder 811-824)
    - Woolsey, Gamel, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 825-837)
    - Woolsey, Gamel (transcripts made by Kenneth Hopkins), 1930 Aug-45 Jan (Box 48, Folder 838-842)
    - Woolsey, Gamel (transcripts made by Kenneth Hopkins), 1945-61, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 843-857)
    - Woolsey, Gamel (transcripts made by Kenneth Hopkins), n.d. (Box 50, Folder 858)
      With letters from Hopkins to others, 1979-83
    - Woolsey, Gamel (to Wilkinson, Joan Lamburn), 1951 Dec 17 (Box 50, Folder 859)
    - Wordsworth, Giles, 1952-67, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 860-868)
    - [Wright?], David, 1964-66 (Box 50, Folder 869)
    - Wright, James
      See: London Magazine, Box 18, folder 316
    - Zigrosser, Carl, 1964-66, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 870)
    - -----, George, 1943, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 871)
    - -----, Hytie, 1963-64, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 872)
    - Unidentified, 1929-67, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 873-875)
  - GREGORY AND PINNEO FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Byington, Jean L. Gregory
      Sometimes called "Jeannette"
      - AG (Box 51, Folder 876)
      - Gregory, James G., 1904 Apr 19 (Box 51, Folder 877)